Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/barunroy (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Agile Methodologies Project Management TIBCO BW

Certifications

Certified Scrum Product Owner (CSPO)

TOGAF

AWS Certified DevOps Engineer – Professional

Barun Roy

Principal Architect/Associate Director at Cognizant Technology Solutions

Kolkata, West Bengal, India

Summary

TOGAF certified Architect with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry. Have more than 13 years industry experience in EAI and related technologies primarily using TIBCO suites of products. Possesses extensive work experience for working in all phases of SDLF life cycle including 72 months working experience in client location (USA).

Quick learner and fond of learning new technologies.

Experience

Cognizant

14 years 10 months

Associate Director

January 2022 - Present (3 years)

Kolkata, West Bengal, India

Senior Architect

June 2016 - March 2022 (5 years 10 months)

Kolkata Area, India

Architect

June 2012 - June 2016 (4 years 1 month)

Technology Specialist

March 2010 - May 2012 (2 years 3 months)

Onsite coordinator and Analyst.

Tata Consultancy Services

6 years 3 months

TIBCO Consultant

March 2004 - March 2010 (6 years 1 month)

Achieved TIBCO BW 5.0 Certification last year.

Working actively in several TIBCO products. Have worked in RV and EMS 5.0

ITA

January 2004 - March 2010 (6 years 3 months)

Education

Kalyani University

B.Tech., Mechanical · (1999 - 2003)

Sikkim Manipal University - Distance Education

Master of Business Administration - MBA, Information Systems · (2010 - 2013)

Rahara Ramkrishna Mission V C College

Higher Secondary, Science · (1997 - 1999)

Sodepur High School

Secondary · (1991 - 1997)

Balaram Siksha Mandir

Primary Education · (1986 - 1991)